[{"id": "590678e5ff9c0647b50a804d", "question": "What month, in 2016, did the World Trade Organization announce an outbreak of the Zika virus?", "answer": "January", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef66956ce05a3942286e79", "question": "Which musician was the original \"Thomas the Tank Engine\" narrator on TV?", "answer": "Ringo Starr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b214", "question": "Who was assassinated by Nathuram Godse?", "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b8d5532b42d4a3561a9f01", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is the name of the advertising company Francine interviews for and gets mocked at in the elevator?", "answer": "RBK&S", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb2d", "question": "Someone who raises false alarms is said to cry what?", "answer": "Wolf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec849eec223966ae8f8800", "question": "Sozin's comet is an astrological event that occurs in which television series?", "answer": "\"Avatar: the Last Airbender\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66c9752a821ff76ae8b13", "question": "Prior to 1954, Veterans Day was known as what in the US?", "answer": "Armistice Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a789", "question": "Which US state borders most of Narrangansett Bay?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b877", "question": "What crayon did Crayola rename to \"peach\" in 1962?", "answer": "Flesh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c045", "question": "What's the triangular Asian pastry containing spiced meat?", "answer": "Samosa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede4226ce05a3942286dd8", "question": "What was the name of the 1976 Led Zeppelin concert film?", "answer": "The Song Remains the Same", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba1f5874c93a3298b212d", "question": "Which city is the capital of the Austrian state of Tyrol?", "answer": "Innsbruck", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c225", "question": "What is the primary type of alcohol in the cocktail Mai Tai?", "answer": "Rum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a855", "question": "\"Lost City of the Incas\" is another name for what Peruvian site?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef92a66ce05a3942286e86", "question": "What was the first animated TV series to win an Emmy?", "answer": "Huckleberry Hound Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b08d01dd7bf43be5e78e", "question": "What company created the first mass-produced portable computer?", "answer": "Osborne Computers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f8abfa5fdd6dd25324f0", "question": "Which city is home to Colman's mustard?", "answer": "Norwich", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec26378dc25ca9e12ef648", "question": "Which country has been donating London's Trafalgar's Square's Christmas tree since 1947?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af24bb8844f4236002b95b0", "question": "The names of how many countries start with the letter \"A\"?", "answer": "12", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff5", "question": "Who was the first African American to host a TV show?", "answer": "Nat King Cole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eaf37f83302ff91e46491", "question": "What does the word \"khaki\" literally translate to in English?", "answer": "Soil-colored", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd71", "question": "Who condensed milk for first time in the US in 1856?", "answer": "Gail Borden, Jr.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59523e16736d4be723796b4a", "question": "In which Canadian city would you find the largest mall in North America?", "answer": "Edmonton", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b58", "question": "What Broadway Musical is based off the opera \"La Bohem\"?", "answer": "Rent", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a7fd6c0f9723ab15cb61", "question": "What are the names of the \"see no evil, hear no evil, speak no evil\" monkey statues?", "answer": "Mizaru, Kikazaru, and Iwazaru", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a8", "question": "Defenestration is the act of being thrown out of what?", "answer": "A window", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2e", "question": "What company bought naming rights to the Florida Suncoast Dome in 1996?", "answer": "Tropicana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "595642f2803c1f1ebcc4a02e", "question": "Who took home the Academy of Country Music\u2019s Male Vocalist trophy every year between 2006 and 2010?", "answer": "Brad Paisley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f0f2ff048f679a45aaac", "question": "Wiccaphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Witches and witchcraft", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c7c", "question": "What is Indiana Jones' daytime occupation?", "answer": "Professor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b1", "question": "Frank Oz performed the character of which Muppet until the early 2000's?", "answer": "Miss Piggy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be57f6c5415ba52ed6f0aaa", "question": "What type of creature is a \"sidewinder\"?", "answer": "A snake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a2", "question": "Who was the youngest member of \"The Traveling Wilbury's\"?", "answer": "Tom Petty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa4f86ce05a3942286eba", "question": "What duo first recorded the song \"Careless Whisper\"?", "answer": "Wham!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a541", "question": "Which US state is home to Crater Lake National Park?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9e", "question": "In Rudyard Kipling's \"The Jungle Book\", what type of animal was Kaa?", "answer": "A snake", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339195", "question": "What was the first CD ever pressed in the US?", "answer": "Bruce Springsteen's Born in the USA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb4ee65ff7d326b622a8a", "question": "In what play do we follow Aaron, a Moor beloved of Tamora?", "answer": "Titus Andronicus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399bf", "question": "What was Captain Stubing's first name, on the TV show \"The Love Boat\"?", "answer": "Merrill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fe71a4edfd43a087adce", "question": "What does a ventriloquist typically hold on their lap?", "answer": "A puppet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59068390ff9c0647b50a80a8", "question": "How many original shows and movies did Netflix release in 2016?", "answer": "45", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb0f", "question": "In what country is Guinness Stout brewed?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ad", "question": "What baseball hall-of-famer was nicknamed \"Hammerin' Hank\"?", "answer": "Hank Aaron", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab1b3ef4fda37788a9a1dc5", "question": "Where is the Salvador Dali museum located?", "answer": "St. Petersburg, Florida", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f9", "question": "In what state did former Illinois Governor Rod Blagojavich begin serving his 14 year sentence for corruption?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a96a", "question": "Gouda and Edam are cities in what country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79c", "question": "What is the name of Neptune's largest moon?", "answer": "Triton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c909", "question": "What name is given to animals which eat both plants and meat?", "answer": "Omnivore", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96dca23c87fd04dd15e2f", "question": "Who sculpted Mount Rushmore?", "answer": "Gutzon Borglum", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133904b", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"The Giant\"?", "answer": "Sergei Prokofiev", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e7", "question": "What US state has been led by Woodrow Wilson and Jim McGreevey?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e3", "question": "What letter in the alphabet is the only one with more than one syllable?", "answer": "W", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b8", "question": "What does a decibel measure?", "answer": "Sound Pressure Level", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5902a14acad1ec93f27df775", "question": "In a Cortado, what is the main purpose of the milk?", "answer": "To reduce the acidity of the coffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6f7", "question": "What is the name of the process of splitting atomic nuclei?", "answer": "Fission", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8aa1c01dd7bf43be5e757", "question": "What is the Hebrew term for \"commandment\"?", "answer": "Mitzvah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a798", "question": "What five countries border Peru?", "answer": "Colombia, Ecuador, Brazil, Bolivia and Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a6", "question": "What movie starred Mel Gibson as William Wallace?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008e07df4f3bc4a292f8632", "question": "Who said \"The journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step\"?", "answer": "Lao Tzu (The Chinese philosopher's quote about great things having humble beginnings comes from his famous work, \"Tao Te Ching\".)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a307", "question": "Who played the role of David Duchovny's daughter on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Madeleine Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b384", "question": "Mary Read and Anne Bonny had what job in common?", "answer": "Pirates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac7", "question": "Indianapolis is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Indiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b54e01dd7bf43be5e7ce", "question": "What are Bic pens named after?", "answer": "A version of the founder's name", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5ff36ce05a3942286e48", "question": "In what movie did Schwartz \"triple-dog-dare\" Flick to stick his tongue on a flagpole?", "answer": "\"A Christmas Story\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b795", "question": "Christmas caroling began as what old English custom?", "answer": "Wassailing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b11d", "question": "In what year did Aaron Burr kill Alexander Hamilton in a duel?", "answer": "1804", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1d1", "question": "When not fighting crime, what did Underdog do for a living?", "answer": "Shoeshine boy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bce", "question": "In what year did ABBA become officially a group?", "answer": "1973", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339212", "question": "What rock star is credited as a co-writer and backing singer for David Bowie's \"Fame\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae88", "question": "What general became a national hero for his defense of New Orleans during the War of 1812?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c902", "question": "What is the fear of nudity known as?", "answer": "Gymnophobia or Nudophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ef", "question": "What has the largest eyes in the world?", "answer": "Colossal Squid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133892b", "question": "Thor is the son of which Norse god?", "answer": "Odin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c4af877e98cb977789a3", "question": "Which two African countries merged into Tanzania?", "answer": "Tanganyika and Zanzibar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e0", "question": "What is the capital of Florida?", "answer": "Tallahassee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e9a43ebfabb9c85d8a979", "question": "The meat pie, Tourtiere, originated in which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008cdfcf842fa4c4ba96a3", "question": "Warsaw is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fbaebc10738315b1fb74e2c", "question": "What Shakesperian play involves love between a Roman Soldier and the Queen of Egypt?", "answer": "Antony and Cleopatra", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bebb", "question": "The South Beach Diet is named for a section of what city?", "answer": "Miami Beach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b56b", "question": "What is Lipton the world's biggest-selling brand of?", "answer": "Tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d6", "question": "Who had to face the multi-headed Hydra in the second of his labors?", "answer": "Hercules", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6cd", "question": "Jaundice tends to turn one's skin, and sometimes the whites of the eyes, what color?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958b", "question": "Who plays the role of Sarah Jordan in the 2005 movie \"The Island\"?", "answer": "Scarlett Johansson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cb70e62f96e155acab35d39", "question": "Who played the role of Alan in the \"The Hangover\" movies?", "answer": "Zach Galifianakis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e4", "question": "What hangs from the roof of a limestone cave?", "answer": "Stalactites", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c90cf1f52800b05cac20f07", "question": "What US state receives the most annual rainfall?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59008f30cf842fa4c4ba96b9", "question": "Italian painter Jacopo Comin is better known as who?", "answer": "Tintoretto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c7", "question": "US President James Garfield died of what cause?", "answer": "He was shot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f0f", "question": "What author created the character of Dr. Gideon Fell?", "answer": "John Dickson Carr", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be9a", "question": "What pro wrestler grew up next door to playwright Samuel Beckett?", "answer": "Andre the Giant", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398be", "question": "What superhero's enemies include the Joker, the Penguin and the Riddler?", "answer": "Batman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2bc", "question": "What are the three main types of sugar?", "answer": "Glucose, fructose and sucrose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e7", "question": "Who founded the e-commerce retailer Amazon?", "answer": "Jeff Bezos", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c1cc877e98cb9777897d", "question": "What does Salzburg translate to?", "answer": "Salt Castle", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beb1", "question": "What title was given to Nanak, the founder of Sikhism?", "answer": "Guru", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf66", "question": "What is the practice of women taking more than one husband is called?", "answer": "Polyandry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad43", "question": "Which country seized the USS Pueblo after accusing its American crew of unlawful spying in 1968?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b548", "question": "What day is hump day?", "answer": "Wednesday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be87", "question": "What type of a tree killed Albert Camus?", "answer": "Plane tree", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e2c", "question": "What musical was based on Thornton Wilder's play \"The Matchmaker\"?", "answer": "Hello, Dolly!", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c263", "question": "What grows in a paddy field?", "answer": "Rice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339479", "question": "Who won an Oscar for Best Actor in 1993 and again in 1994?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad8", "question": "Nyala are a type of antelope that are indigenous to which continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973b", "question": "What do the letters stand for in the band CCR?", "answer": "Creedence Clearwater Revival", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc3", "question": "Albania has coasts on which two seas?", "answer": "Adriatic and Ionian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e17bfe83fe1f2a824b94", "question": "What major mistake did the Allies make in preparing to defend against Germany\u2019s attack on France?", "answer": "They misinterpreted where the main invasion would take place", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a53b", "question": "What US city is nicknamed the \"Motor City\"?", "answer": "Detroit", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c28a", "question": "What element's chemical symbol is Pb?", "answer": "Lead's", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe3eafe38e4e5d4832e6317", "question": "Which company produced the World War II fighter plane \"Spitfire\"?", "answer": "Triumph", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b5a", "question": "What was the first ever animated film to be nominated for the Best Picture Oscar?", "answer": "Beauty and the Beast", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c817", "question": "What would a doctor call \"pes planus\"?", "answer": "Fallen arches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac0", "question": "Lake Erie contains an artificial reef made from the pieces of which sports stadium demolished in 1996?", "answer": "Cleveland Municipal Stadium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b058e662d71a53650fc6", "question": "Which museum owns the only Da Vinci painting in the Western Hemisphere?", "answer": "National Art Gallery (U.S.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4e3", "question": "What letter appears on the left end of the bottom letter row of a traditional QWERTY keyboard?", "answer": "The letter Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338965", "question": "What year was the popular French comic first published?", "answer": "1959", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f6a", "question": "Who is the only American-born member of Monty Python?", "answer": "Terry Gilliam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a551d83e1c6f9840ba3190", "question": "What is a \"Pickelhaube\"?", "answer": "A spiked German helmet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae0", "question": "What small carrier attached to a motorcycle shares its name with a brandy cocktail?", "answer": "Sidecar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c8", "question": "Whose first film was the documentary \"Roger & Me\"?", "answer": "Michael Moore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede4d06ce05a3942286de2", "question": "On which real-life serial killer was the killer in the film \"Scream\" based?", "answer": "Danny Rolling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f4e82af848b908361b882", "question": "What year was Pinterest launched?", "answer": "2010", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c383", "question": "The water moccasin snake is also known as what?", "answer": "Cottonmouth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a893", "question": "What city is home to the Shukhov Tower?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339826", "question": "What were Laurel and Hardy's first names?", "answer": "Stan and Oliver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e90fd7fd7247dfc0fa00307", "question": "Who is the first Prime Minister of Italy, also a leading figure in the Italian unification?", "answer": "Camillo Benso", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab99cbd21a8909e5c332d39", "question": "Corsica is part of which country?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918a", "question": "How many keys does a baby grand piano have?", "answer": "88", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc74aec223966ae8f888c", "question": "There have only been five \"quadruple-doubles\" achieved in the NBA. Which player is responsible for two of them?", "answer": "Hakeem Olajuwon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c389877e98cb97778995", "question": "Which country has a presidential office known as \"the Pink House\"?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dea", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"caboose\"?", "answer": "Dutch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59c1ce3f7bd84c0ea43ad435", "question": "On which river does the capital of Canada lie?", "answer": "Ottawa River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909cd39bb53d1af658864e7", "question": "What gives traditional eggnog its frothy texture?", "answer": "Whipped eggs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339110", "question": "In which play by Tennessee Williams would you encounter the character \"Big Daddy\"?", "answer": "Cat on a Hot Tin Roof", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e1b", "question": "What's the real name of the Gary Glitter track often called \"The Hey Song\"?", "answer": "Rock and Roll (Part Two)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ba", "question": "Which planet orbits the Sun the quickest?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133931b", "question": "In the 2002 movie \"Spiderman\", what was Peter Parker's profession?", "answer": "Photographer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c0", "question": "What animal has the highest blood pressure of any animal?", "answer": "The giraffe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b763", "question": "In soccer, how many yellow cards result in a red card?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a236", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Business as Usual\" in 1981?", "answer": "Men at Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cae9", "question": "Who is credited with inventing and patenting the radial tire in 1915?", "answer": "Arthur W. Savage", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ba", "question": "What city is home to the headquarters of the Boeing Company?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8a93801dd7bf43be5e74a", "question": "Which animal symbolizes good luck in Europe?", "answer": "Ladybug", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c9f78cb4e2c7fbd389674a", "question": "What popular French apple brandy is made by distilling cider made from selected apples?", "answer": "Calvados", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe90a3001dd7bf43be5e897", "question": "What animal has the largest brain?", "answer": "Sperm whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937ed6108d98002fdd633c8", "question": "The song \"Almost Unreal\" by Roxette was the lead single from the soundtrack to which 1993 film?", "answer": "Super Mario Bros.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedddd06ce05a3942286da7", "question": "Red's full name in the film \"The Shawshank Redemption\" is what?", "answer": "Ellis Boyd Redding", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbe276ce05a3942286ee9", "question": "The film \"The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo\" is set in what country?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec7", "question": "The album \"American Beauty/American Psycho\" was released in 2015 by which American rock band?", "answer": "Fall Out Boy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4b9949076251badbeac5", "question": "The Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race was inspired in part by what event?", "answer": "A diphtheria outbreak -- In 1925, several teams of mush dogs relayed a serum for diphtheria from Seward to Nome, Alaska.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391de", "question": "Who played Mr. Blonde in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Michael Madsen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339938", "question": "Who played the main character in the 1997 movie \"Mr. Magoo\"?", "answer": "Leslie Nielsen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febac517e83c707845b20ec", "question": "What is the scientific name of the \"western lowland gorilla\"?", "answer": "Gorilla gorilla gorilla", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b09a", "question": "Which English King signed the Magna Carta in 1215?", "answer": "King John", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8fe", "question": "How far is the free throw line from the backboard in basketball?", "answer": "15 feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe766f8eec85e375820b28c", "question": "The 1979 Soviet invasion of what nearby nation caused an international uproar?", "answer": "Afghanistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6d", "question": "What are the names of the four Musketeers?", "answer": "Athos, Aramis, Porthos and D\u2019artagnan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c455877e98cb9777899d", "question": "Where is the oldest brewery in North America?", "answer": "Montreal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c885", "question": "How many arms does a squid have?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f46", "question": "What 1995 film was Robert Rodriguez's big-budget follow-up to the low-budget hit \"El Mariachi\"?", "answer": "Desperado", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba11", "question": "What is the official state sport of Alaska?", "answer": "Dog mushing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd5", "question": "Farnsworth Bentley became famous for holding whose umbrellas?", "answer": "Puff Daddy's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c020", "question": "Who is the inventor of the cash register?", "answer": "James Ritty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a342", "question": "What kind of a doll grabs Robbie and drags him under his bed in the 1982 film \"Poltergeist\"?", "answer": "A clown doll", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ec2b24043630d44e5be228e", "question": "The Kentucky Derby, Preakness Stakes and Belmont Stakes comprise which series?", "answer": "Triple Crown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b15", "question": "In which decade did the \"Peanuts\" comic strip debut?", "answer": "1950s", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390f0", "question": "Who painted \"The Boy in the Red Vest\"?", "answer": "Paul C\u00e9zanne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e147973dd42e4a67cb8d3ee", "question": "What were the 14 haunting paintings Francisco Goya painted in the later years of his life called?", "answer": "The \"Black Paintings\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac1c", "question": "What is the capital of Suriname?", "answer": "Paramaribo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8fc", "question": "According to Toucan Sam, what should you always follow to find Froot Loops?", "answer": "Your nose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d2", "question": "What did Harry Houdini die from on Halloween in 1926?", "answer": "Ruptured appendix", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b174634bb2d29f81593b706", "question": "What duo lost their Grammy for Best New Artist in the early 1990's?", "answer": "Milli Vanilli", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f164c83f9b80650dbe7f92f", "question": "Who plays Thor in the 2017 film \"Thor: Ragnarok\"?", "answer": "Chris Hemsworth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af6", "question": "Which character killed Albus Dumbledore?", "answer": "Severus Snape", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd0", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"E\"?", "answer": "Echo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d1", "question": "What actress portrayed the title character in the 1965 big-screen Western \"Cat Ballou\"?", "answer": "Jane Fonda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c619", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Gold?", "answer": "Au", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e5", "question": "What is known as a \"Magnum Opus\"?", "answer": "The greatest, most popular or most renowned achievement of a writer, artist or composer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb09", "question": "What do pumpkins grow on?", "answer": "Vines", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e1b", "question": "Who began his famous penance by killing and skinning the Nemean lion?", "answer": "Hercules", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bad", "question": "How many nights are there in \"Arabian Nights\"?", "answer": "1001", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b813", "question": "What is the Jewish New Year called?", "answer": "Rosh Hashanah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e0", "question": "In The Simpsons who said: \"I got a home remedy that'll put the zowzers back in your trousers.\"?", "answer": "Abe SImpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6bd", "question": "The first satellites to visit Venus, Mars, & Mercury were all named what?", "answer": "Mariner", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b979", "question": "What was the fabled city of gold that some 16th century Europeans believed existed in South America?", "answer": "El Dorado", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe522a01bf59ab7d2e380e8", "question": "Who did Nicolas Cage marry in 2002?", "answer": "Lisa Marie Presley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909cfb6bb53d1af658864f5", "question": "The song \"Jingle Bell Rock\" is performed during the opening credits of which \"Lethal Weapon\" film?", "answer": "The first one", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e98a0ebfabb9c85d8a96d", "question": "What is the name for the creamy liver of lobster eaten as a delicacy?", "answer": "Tomalley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb29", "question": "What boxer is memorialized by a giant fist outside Detroit's Renaissance Center?", "answer": "Joe Louis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c00c", "question": "In the tech field, what does AMD stand for?", "answer": "Advanced Micro Devices", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd3", "question": "At age 17, who played the title schoolgirl in \"The Bachelor and the Bobby-Soxer\"?", "answer": "Shirley Temple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339736", "question": "In the TV series \"Lost\", which airline's plane crashed?", "answer": "Oceanic Airlines", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedda536ce05a3942286d84", "question": "Brothers Barry, Robin and Maurice Gibb formed which successful pop group in the late 1950's?", "answer": "Bee Gees", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133960b", "question": "Who played Captain Leo Davidson in the 2001 version of the movie \"Planet of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Mark Wahlberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a067", "question": "What country is the band \"Men Without Hats\" originally from?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd668aba5bfecdd737e0871", "question": "What is the best-selling cookie brand in the world?", "answer": "Oreo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f74701dd7bf43be5e836", "question": "The board game Parcheesi is based off a board game from what country?", "answer": "India", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c61c", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Helium?", "answer": "He", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab89", "question": "Phnom Penh is the capital of which Asian country?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea34e2ff048f679a45aafd", "question": "Which is the densest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071f8a3745b36be73039eb", "question": "The comic book series \"Revival\" is often described as what literary genre?", "answer": "Horror/Rural-noir", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339580", "question": "In which sci-fi movie does an alien race live on Earth in slum-like conditions in South Africa?", "answer": "District 9", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8aacb01dd7bf43be5e761", "question": "What is the official German name of the Swiss Federal Railways?", "answer": "Schweizerische Bundesbahnen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e271fe83fe1f2a824b9f", "question": "Which country was the site of most of the Nazi extermination camps?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067a93ff9c0647b50a805b", "question": "What date did the United Kingdom European Union membership referendum took place on?", "answer": "June 23, 2016", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921f", "question": "What is the collective name for Italian-made western movies?", "answer": "Spaghetti westerns", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a140", "question": "In what film does Steve McQueen get to race a Mustang round the streets of San Francisco?", "answer": "Bullitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f4", "question": "When does Mary Poppins say she will leave?", "answer": "When the wind changes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "591c34c5815febcc896f9255", "question": "Which is the Earth's largest continent?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59049d61cf93664eb10486ad", "question": "Julia Louis-Dreyfus was born on Friday, January 13, of what year?", "answer": "1961", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc4", "question": "In 2006, David Bowie was awarded a Grammy award for what?", "answer": "Lifetime Achievement", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e5", "question": "What popular Motown group was originally known as \"The Primettes\"?", "answer": "The Supremes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf3b", "question": "What drink is a mixture of brandy, egg yolks and sugar?", "answer": "Advocaat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c784", "question": "Aeolian processes pertain to the study of what weather activity?", "answer": "Winds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b0", "question": "Which European country is divided into areas called Cantons?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ded33fea2747c8aff16d46", "question": "What type of a clothing item is a \"Sam Browne\"?", "answer": "A belt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d06d67870e6f05ba600858", "question": "What metals is Bell metal an alloy of?", "answer": "Tin and copper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab0d", "question": "What is the capital of Greece?", "answer": "Athens", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c90d3ce52800b05cac20f19", "question": "Approximately, how many days is the rotation period of Venus?", "answer": "243 days", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c9", "question": "What is the term for a wolf's home?", "answer": "Den", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e93a900d6f11f394a3b2d5a", "question": "In the manga series \"Bleach\", what is the name of Byakuya Kuchiki's zanpakuto?", "answer": "Senbonzakura", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b766", "question": "The phrase \"sticky wickeet\" has its origins in what sport?", "answer": "Cricket", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fab", "question": "What peace activist was the emcee at Woodstock?", "answer": "Wavy Gravy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c3", "question": "What hit 1992 movie gave Geena Davis the chance to prove she could spit?", "answer": "A League of their Own", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe3f0798b5801b8f54a7fbb", "question": "Vienna's famous Sch\u00f6nbrunn Palace is home to the world's oldest what?", "answer": "Zoo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd8d", "question": "What did Teleworld, Inc. rename itself in 1999, after its flagship product?", "answer": "TiVo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1f", "question": "Alphabetically, which is the last of Santa's reindeers?", "answer": "Vixen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d7", "question": "In Norse mythology, what was the name of the monster killed by Beowulf?", "answer": "Grendel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a510", "question": "Which two independent states exist within Italy's borders?", "answer": "Vatican City and San Marino", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c97a", "question": "The North Star is also known as?", "answer": "Polaris", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d0662596a59cbdfbd37b", "question": "Who said, \"Whenever I hear anyone arguing for slavery, I feel a strong impulse to see it tried on him personally\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd664cfa5bfecdd737e0858", "question": "What animal does cashmere come from?", "answer": "Goat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bbb", "question": "What Beatles movie features bad guys called Blue Meanies?", "answer": "Yellow Submarine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c6f49076251badbead4", "question": "Who once owned the land on which Arlington National Cemetery is situated?", "answer": "Confederate General Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e05", "question": "What show debuted on September 7, 1979, with George Grande anchoring?", "answer": "SportsCenter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399cd", "question": "Who won an acting Oscar for their role in the movie \"An Officer and a Gentleman\"?", "answer": "Louis Gossett, Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338921", "question": "Although he is from hell, what symbol does Spawn cling to?", "answer": "A cross", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e0", "question": "In the culinary world, what does \"Amuse-bouche\" literally translate to in English?", "answer": "Mouth amuser", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339512", "question": "Who was the first actor in history to decline an Oscar?", "answer": "George C. Scott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b94", "question": "What kind of animal is called a heffalump, in Winnie the Pooh?", "answer": "An Elephant", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a728c786bcd28c119383287", "question": "How many events are there in a heptathalon?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc3", "question": "Which country was the scene of the Mau Mau rebellion in the 1950s?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cb41877e98cb97778a17", "question": "The ancient Phoenician city of Constantine is located in what modern-day Arab country?", "answer": "Algeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c93e", "question": "What is a group of bears called?", "answer": "Sleuth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339239", "question": "Who performed \"Bitter Sweet Symphony\" with Coldplay at the Live 8 concert?", "answer": "Richard Ashcroft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a809", "question": "What US state capital city lies at the western edge of its state's Bluegrass Region?", "answer": "Frankfort", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab0b36baab681b09292166", "question": "Who was the first king of Jerusalem?", "answer": "King Saul", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e77", "question": "During what war was \"The Iliad\" set?", "answer": "Trojan War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1f", "question": "A nilometer measures the level of what?", "answer": "The river Nile", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339feb", "question": "Queen and Duran Duran both had drummers with what name?", "answer": "Roger Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e86", "question": "What species are mingled to produce a Centaur?", "answer": "Human and horse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c445", "question": "What fluid is stored in the gallbladder?", "answer": "Bile", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b7", "question": "Prior to 2016, which pitcher was the last to win back to back Cy Young Awards in the American League?", "answer": "Pedro Martinez", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc1f1ec223966ae8f8870", "question": "Who\u2019s the only athlete who ever lit the cauldron for an Olympics and then won a gold medal at those same games?", "answer": "Cathy Freeman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989aa42cb8751d53e7d7603", "question": "Who served as the United States Ambassador to Japan from 2013-2017?", "answer": "Caroline Bouvier Kennedy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a992661d1b4d384d5d697", "question": "What year did the TV show \"Gunsmoke\" change its length from 30 minutes to 1 hour?", "answer": "1961", "category": "entertainment"}]